# JIHAD MAROUN LOTFI

## **OVERVIEW**

After completing my secondary education in Lebanon, I traveled to Sydney, Australia, where I attended a university foundation program, and graduated with an Australian high-school equivalent in the stream of media and communications. Following that, I studied architecture at The University of Sydney, and graduated in 2012. My work experience commenced afterwards in Doha, Qatar, at a design-contracting company, where I have contributed to several high-end residential and commercial 'design-build' projects.

Pursuant to my professional experience in Doha, I relocated to Italy where I attended a Master's in Sustainable Architecture & Landscape Design. Following that, after returning to Lebanon in late 2018, I progressed to working on holistic sustainable design projects consolidating architecture, landscaping, agriculture, business viability, and post-completion enterprise operation. Most recently, I have completed a 7-month project with a local NGO, focused on the rehabilitation of residential units affected by the Beirut Explosion of August 2020.

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: November 25<sup>th</sup>, 1987 Place of birth: Beirut-Lebanon Nationality: Lebanese

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Architect/Project Officer (Residential unit rehabilitation)

Basmeh & Zeitooneh - Lebanon: September 2020-April 2021

B&Z head office, Rizkallah Semaan St, Furn Al Shebbak-Beirut, Lebanon

- Damage assessment of residential units & buildings affected by the Beirut Explosion of August 2020
- Documentation of damages and the creation of itemised lists of rehabilitation works and bills of quantities
- Proposition of optimal rehabilitation solutions in collaboration with contractors and tradesmen
- Ensuring rehabilitation work's compliance with international design standards, buildings codes, & construction guidelines
- Supervising work execution until completion and handover, to the satisfaction of beneficiaries
- Household vulnerability assessment, comparisons, and deciding on intervention based on established criteria
- Estimating costs and working timeframes for rehabilitation work per unit

#### Architect (Design/residential, agritourism & commercial)

Freelance - Lebanon: November 2018-September 2020

Beirut, Lebanon

- Design conceptualisation and development
- Creating interior, architecture, and productive landscaping solutions
- Production of CAD drawings, design presentations, and 3D visualisations
- Synthesizing holistic land and enterprise development strategies consolidating among architecture, landscaping, environmental, social and economic sustainability, as well as operational solutions

## Project Architect (Design-Construction/High-end residential & commercial)

G.E.T. (General Engineering Technologies) - Qatar: February 2013-February 2017

Level 3, Al Muftah Plaza, Rayan Road- Doha, Qatar

- Team leader-architectural, landscape & interior design
- Production and presentation of design proposals to clients
- Preparation & supervision of IFC (Issued For Construction) drawings and submittal
- Preparation & supervision of architectural, interior & landscape shop-drawings

- Interdisciplinary coordination
- Consultant, client and designer engagement and coordination
- Sub-contractor relations
- Material and product selection and specification
- Design revision & development, for quality control, construction and compliance with regulations
- Work and material inspection
- Calculation of material quantities and BOQ preparation

#### **EDUCATION**

Sustainable Architecture & Landscape Design

Politecnico di Milano- Piacenza- Italy

2017-2018

Bachelor of Design in Architecture

University of Sydney - Sydney- Australia

2007-2012

University of Sydney Foundation Program-Media & Communications

Taylors College-Sydney-Australia

2006

## **SKILLS**

- -Architectural design and detailing
- -Interior design, joinery & detailing
- -Sustainable design and passive-environmental control
- -Residential unit rehabilitation
- -Team management
- -Graphic design & presentation
- -Development applications
- -Construction and shop drawing production
- -AutoCAD 2007-2021
- -Google SketchUp + V-Ray rendering engine
- -Adobe Photoshop
- -Adobe Illustrator
- -Microsoft Office
- -Physical architectural modeling
- -Photography
- -Technical & creative writing

#### LANGUAGES

Arabic

English

## **INTERESTS**

Visual arts, music, poetry, sustainability, nature and beyond

## **WORK REFEREES**

Ex Manager (Rehabilitations Project Manager) Ex Manager (General Project Manager) Ex Manager (Head of Interior Design) Other referees provided upon request +974 4434 1730 +974 4434 1730 provided upon request Mohammad Moustafa eliassaba@get-eng.com tarekramadan@get-eng.com

# PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Residential unit rehabilitations with B&Z

(restored)

No. of completed units (individually) 80 across 11 zones

Scope of intervention: glazing & fenestration, doors, surface finishing, waterproofing, sanitary fixtures and plumbing, electrical, privacy & safety works

Harik Snack

(restored)

(design phase 1 proposal)

(concept proposal)

Shop Area: 30 SOM

Description: F&B outlet/restored post Beirut Blast of Aug. 2020

Nahle Highland Farm

(concept proposal) Built-up Area: 2,556 SOM

Plot Area: 5,084 SQM

Description: Multi-purpose Sustainable Agritourism Farm

Treasure Trail-Lebanon

Built-up Area: 508 SQM Plot Area: 3,388 SQM

Description: Multi-purpose Sustainable Agritourism Farm

Floor Area: 985 SQM

Description: Pilot Model Business Centre Design

Voco Hotel Business Centre Revamp-UAE

Schneider House-Germany (to be constructed)

Floor Area: 144 SQM

Description: Stand-alone Residential/design consultancy

Al Wakra Village Heritage Hotel 1 (built)

Built-up Area: 8.097 SOM Plot Area: 18,766 SOM

Description: 5-Star boutique hotel in heritage area

Al Wakra Village Heritage Hotel 2 (built)

Built-up Area: 5,806 SQM Plot Area: 10,670 SQM

Description: 5-Star boutique hotel in heritage area

Messila Villa no. 4 (built)

Built-up Area: 2,500 SQM Plot Area: 6,000 SQM

Description: Multi-story high-end residential, with auxiliary buildings.

Messila Villa no. 6 (built)

Built-up Area: 2,500 SQM Plot Area: 6,000 SOM

Description: Multi-story high-end residential, with auxiliary buildings

Al Gharia Beach Villas (built)

Built-up Area: 2,050 SQM Plot Area: 22,500 SQM

Description: A residential beach project with auxiliary buildings

Messila Villa no. 1 (built)

Built-up Area: 4,250 SQM Plot Area: 6018 SQM

Description: Multi-story high-end residential villa with auxiliary buildings

#### **OTHER**

Link to portfolio: https://documentcloud.adobe.com/link/review?uri=urn:aaid:scds:US:2e82c266-275f-4d7c-a088-104d11461b71 LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jlotfi/